oh wait till a few people saw some fun
to get before you read the paper all
right so the reason we're eating this
paper so I check out archived sanity a
lot it's pretty good and I think it was
in top recent there's this paper out
called glow from open AI well okay so
there's this paper called wave glow and
then I looked up below by open AI in
general you know this is how citations
work right if you track them back you
eventually get to better papers so then
this paper came out called glue and then
this paper referred to this paper nice
nonlinear independent components
explanation estimation I don't really
understand what that means but on the
glow thing either like you know look you
can like change how much just for one is
smiling like look you can really make
her smile that looks painful
we can make a smile not at all we can
make her old and sad oh she's old with a
sad look at her butt oh little see
that's better Wow
Walt's your blonde hair and no beard no
way Oh beautiful
but yeah so apparently they did this
unsupervised or like they're claiming to
by by using whatever his trick is
contained in this paper we propose a
deep learning framework for modeling
complex high dimensional densities
called alright
so let's try to figure out what a
density means in this context oh I'm
sorry my chat I haven't been looking at
my chat not that what's up yeah no yeah
we're reading so we're reading this
paper today oh I like that idea we can
make a reading group oh with your new
paper every day um so let me bring up
the chat on my phone again so I can see
the UH
is the bandwidth bad they all look so
good
well okay maybe not so bad kind of okay
yeah I cut off the top of my screen I
figured that was the best way to deal
with the fact that my monitor is not
sixteen by nine it but it is 16 by 10 oh
let's go to my chat oh here we go
I'm down for the plant I only ever get a
rant or two while reading well we read
you know like rice with terminal reading
paper shop yeah so do what are they all
not supposed to talk loudly in the cloud
but I went to the supermarket today guys
so you guys know that this is the new
drink of choice I take this green tea
delicious green tea that's what I have
right here bro two more cuz they were so
cheap we also have fishes and for
actually more expensive than fishes we
have an individually packaged couple
have you ever seen anything like this so
it's actually the same price as vicious
this is the same price as this these
weren't even 99 yen
these were 79 bro you're getting ripped
off when you go to those machines and
then I got this but we're gonna eat
together on the stream
like an apple pastry tip I had cooked
fishes for dinner but I'm gonna go put
all of these in the fridge and maybe we
will eat the fishes later on the stream
oh they love plastic they'll have
plastic if everything is in plastic all
natural men who remember the natural
mood bro the hotness mmm no we're gonna
eat this one stream
so don't worry we'll also be coding on
this stream it won't just be a I know
you like eating stream it won't just be
when I call this one in 90 Solon
capitals so I have a theory that let's
[Music]
so we have this matrix
and want to be rich with scam stream on
twitch and get people to subscribe to
you think that's what I want
so mmm I'm not saying okay you have pip
pie pot you can use pie pie to run pip
it's like pie pie - M pip or something
um all right before we play around with
this more let's read the paper we're
reading this paper I don't know you guys
are gonna like reading stream but we're
doing readings - don't be racist no
racism on my stream all people eat the
same nope that's true we're reading this
paper we're gonna understand what all
these words mean so this guy's famous
y'all know he's famous but here's a star
next to his name oh well we got it
always a c4 senior fellow complex high
dimensional densities so I think what
they're saying here is like if you have
like a picture right you can think about
a picture where each pixels dimension
and then you can think of like the
pictures people's faces and those
pictures are embedded like they are in
that high dimensional space first
purpose nonlinear determinative
transformation of data is long it Maps
it onto the latent space so as to make
the transformed data conform to a
factorized distribution resulting in
independent latent variables
improvisation
okay so independent with respect to what
what is a factorize distribution and why
do I need to know the determinant of the
Jacobian stream just started just you're
here $1 the training criteria and
assembly the exact log-likelihood which
is tractable unbiased ancestral sandwich
I don't know what that means
ancestral sample if joint distribution
representation distribution of the data
is easy to mop in this paper we
considered a special case where we asked
the learner to find the transformation
of the data into the new space such that
the resulting distribution factorizes
the components are independent
you know nothing's big in the cloud
everything is just as big as it needs to
be new Tom Cruise how much mass we're
trying to understand this paper okay if
you don't have any constructive comments
to say toward understanding the paper
then you know we're not gonna go can I
post the paper
yeah called nice okay inference sampling
in painting
and the core idea behind this is we can
split X into two blocks
sounds like Lenny around because linear
regression we consider the problem with
learning a probability density for
parametric family of densities over
finite data set D of n samples each
living in a space so that that's where I
was going with with this my samples are
here all right
no Tom Cruise only constructive things
for understanding the paper I'm verbally
warning you anymore non-constructive
things will be given time out on Twitch
because we're here to be constructive no
more rants everybody here is happy I
don't want to totally block you but
we're gonna give you a time out
that's right
vertical pre-processing will transform
the variable proposing can increase
likelihood arbitrarily simply by
contracting the data I guess that's a
reasonable hour in Russia that's why
people are talking in Russian I also use
the change of variables formula equation
one
this is not simple
okay so let's just write down some
definitions here we were asking the trip
they learn how to find a transformation
h equals f of X of the data to a new
space okay so I guess H as the late in
space which assumes F of inverter is
invertible and the dimension of H is the
same as the dimension of X in order to
fit a distribution and I know that P
means
I want pictures too f is invertible you
know we're trying to read this paper
okay here's the name of the paper I'm
going to get a fish I try to read the
paper and we're gonna try only know
Python it would be nice if I do knew
another language but we're reading this
paper today that's what we're doing now
I think Python is actually the
appropriate language here next time we
code something like twitch slammer
twitch chats we always Python but
today's reading day we're gonna see if
reading day we're gonna see how reading
day goes
easy to have another recall in the
easing of universe
give us fish
fish hole finite data set d of n
examples each living in a space
yeah you like this that's good fish fish
is delicious aw bro you don't need a
fish before
this is really hard
P is definitely a distribution um I
don't know maybe this is a stupid stream
that's not what it is that's not from
chemistry maybe this is a stupid stream
with chess guys we were going to try to
read this paper but it turns out this
paper certainly hard maximum-likelihood
using the following will be a predefined
density function
okay well so the distribution of the
hypothesis is just saying is a Gaussian
predefined density function
what is the next project that's a great
question I think so I didn't know about
this paper till today the architecture
of the model is crucial to paint a
family of rejection whose Jacobian okay
I understand like what this means right
like it's obvious what this means but
why yeah
I don't think I need the author to
explain it to me I think I just need to
sit here for an hour the only question
is do I want to sit here with you guys I
don't want to sit here alone is this a
nice stream I don't know is this a good
stream seventy five people are watching
this it is hard I feel like on
stream there should be action you know
yeah I'm tempted to sit alone and this
is what I was doing tonight I thought
I'd bring you guys along make flappybird
[Laughter]
do we want to make flappy bird but what
is flappy bird all right let's make
flappy bird let's go
twitch flappy sure you sure you really
do this this is really what we want to
do we're not gonna learn anything doing
this is
give you something gonna learn something
do it when I'm making shitty flappy bird
all right some scratch and see that
sounds awful you're not gonna learn
anything they're just gonna be
frustrated debugging things no eh I hate
AI
no no no I knew what maximum likelihood
estimation is I we can look it up
I mean yeah it's okay use pencil and
paper to break the equations down and
why is it taking a log okay all right
well okay so these are my new samples
what should we call let's call them big
X all right and now our goal is to find
some function f that's going to turn
this back into that I just multiplied it
by a random matrix this should be doable
yeah you're right you're right I don't
have MATLAB do I have that one I have
that lap well no sirree knowledge okay
they have topcoat I mean the codes
probably easier not nice get up
standard normal
we only support MLP encoder we only
support by objective layers with given
inference compute the log likelihood of
a batch according to the model
distribution okay so we have this X we
can look at the shape of X get F prop
okay so the log likelihood is the prior
plus the log dat Jack get F prop and log
dat dacovian the state of the layer and
log have to go wow okay if self in code
or is not long great
alright so we need the encoder now
see the x4 how to use it
okay so we have some log likelihood of
the prior then if we want a sample from
the distribution we have to have this
thing self encoder okay so let's see
what that set so is instance encoder I'm
okay okay so that's the MLP here this is
the encoder and it's written pi learned
- I don't know the last person who's
written anything in PI learned to his
instance encoder MLP so it should be
like class MLP we're actually the MLP is
just defined here and PI learn two
models MLP I learned who hasn't been
used in centuries multi-layer perceptron
so I mean this is what they used to call
neural networks back in like forever ago
like 2004 just see what the initializer
is for
this possible heart attack and will
appear to be okay so layers batch sighs
now I assume there's an activation
function is there an activation function
has a header encoder see where did these
things come from this sure doesn't have
it
all right so maybe it's only here in
layers so what's a layer blocks brick
base from layer import layer
oh there's a theano one too it's even
find a tensorflow
no there's not we're gonna try to write
one in tensorflow
what try to have tensorflow my Python 3
get high stream no one gets hot here
this is the cloud
should we eat that Apple or should we
save the Apple for tomorrow or should we
get the door is Domino's
that's always an option as well sure
Domino's this Domino's everywhere in the
world man you wanna see how quickly a
man who remembers why it's gotta get
here in 30 minutes or less are your
pizzas free
okay so this just goes through the
layers what are the layers let's just
initialize as a triangular MLP it's not
talked about in the paper or Lu
MLP in our experiments this building
block has a unit Jacobian determinant
for any M as trivially invertible I see
what's trivially invertible at least the
core idea behind this is we can split X
into two blocks how does it split X into
said blocks maybe that's what I don't
understand
the architecture of the model is crucial
to obtain a family of by Jackson's whose
Jacobian determinant is tractable first
we consider affine transformations
[Music]
alright this is the last time we do
paper reading stream guys I forgot how
hard reading paper is any square
matrices this is interesting well
triangular matrices whose determinants
are simply the product of the diagonal
element inverting triangular matrices a
test time okay I mean this is just an
interesting idea and of itself right
like if you have a neural network by
ejective activation functions triangular
Jacobian I mean this interesting idea in
and of itself right like taking the
inverse of a neural network if you have
a neural networks what's the Lu function
the equation for tell you
it's just that so let's say like hey I
want to compute the Lu la Plata and V
dot X X X minus 1 if less than zero oh
yeah so we want to say is numpy and line
yeah
yes we can just do it so I'm gonna do is
plot it we can do this you know
so that's an Lu which is actually an
invertible function which is pretty cool
and matrices are invertible as well so
maybe those are the things that maybe
this is what they're talking about here
the architectural model is crucial to
obtain a family of by Jackson's 2
zoocobia determinate is tractable in
this computation is straightforward it's
actually interesting how yeah like
really invertible most of these things
are many square matrices M can also be
expressed as a product of upper and
lower triangular matrices so this is
like SVD because no SVD triangular
weight matrices and by jected activation
yeah so that's bioactive do I read books
a lot sometimes sometimes you read books
I eat of the axes like the best function
ever don't read any articles
news is for losers losers really do
losers spread news tune out the modern
propaganda do your part there were some
news rise with loser
um boarding of every books like you
can't really read a textbook whoever was
talking about how if you want to like
understand a paper you gotta like write
out the equations and stuff is
absolutely right I'm not much of a
writer I can't really write but I can
tell you so
I don't understand this yes I understand
sampling all right let's just make a
little neural network and then let's
take the inverse of it
well can we make an invertible M nest
it's kind of an interesting idea so it's
cool as new Karass is built into tensor
flow so you can say things like that
I do import tensor flow dr. oz as cross
and then can I say that
oh yeah doesn't work let's see it's
annoying you have to write stupid tensor
flow everywhere it's gonna download
analyst from the internet
Oh
I'm in the cloud Japan is the cloud
pretty much make sure you get your
passport card your passport card
Oh get your passport card also get money
got money gotta get money you know
what's cool about Asia man
all right the best oz stupid question is
this the Geo hot no wrong guy okay so I
mean it just kind of can we take an EM
missed and can we train and can we train
like the typical classifier in that and
then can we invert that net and try to
get it to generate pictures
Claire normal classes is not defined you
guys can see what I'm working hey you
guys can see fine cool okay so we have
this little problem new Tom Cruise
I'm warning some of you guys if you're
not here to be constructive and help
understand the paper you're bad and if
you're a subscriber no no no no we're
banning macbook guy cuz his question was
stupid
wrong guy bro I don't know who that is
see I can't ban you if you're all the
way down there
all right so wills must be vant keeping
track at this account I don't know who
you are
are you subscriber no you're not a
subscriber why would I let you something
y'all are getting banned I wants to be
in charge of banning people which
subscriber would like to be in charge of
banning people not you please subscribe
first subscriber to be like I want to
ban people you're a subscriber
congratulations if I could only if my
stupid thing would work see the problem
is the button to make you mod is further
down we have to wait till a few more
people talk talk talk so then I can
click here and then congratulations ban
all they'll be able to say obnoxious
all right where were we what was my over
here okay so we're gonna try to amnesty
bill thing I think that's like the trick
here um oh I could type mod' name I
remove tab and I'm give them time outs
if they say stupid you asked me if
they should go to college okay see now
whatever I understand is okay so they're
using rel you my understanding of rel
you is that it's not reversible it's
just like their actual paper you don't
have an actual paper just have stars
might be the right one see let's make
sure this is the right one and then like
let's put more effort into reading their
code oh here this guy did it in PI torch
that's probably readable
[Music]
limitation of models from paper pillows
really your network okay so they're
using batch norm I mean I guess that
doesn't really matter they're also using
rel you so I don't understand because
aurelio is not invertible for reference
this is what R Elliot looks like and you
can see how it's not a very by active
function it's also not a differentiable
function they're saying leaky rel use
this Aliki value but if you have a
normal value it's not invertible because
of that big klappa so I don't understand
how they're doing this inverted grant
application of the miles of rivers for
additive coupling layer I don't
understand this build value Network and
if couple later
layer 4 dot universe okay so I guess
this is something they define here maybe
ok layer with coupling law the two
things are of a song base class inherits
from base coupling layer can do this
inverse thing okay I understand this
input dim odd even that doesn't seem
right because a plus B oh I don't know
base coupling layer
[Music]
self dot second oh okay
get even get odd this seems stupid
like it seems like they actually just
divided it in half
yeah okay so I think I see what they're
doing here even valued columns versus
odd value comes this seems extremely
complicated and it seems like it's
literally just designed for the
inpainting problem yeah okay
nobody even or even so then they like
switch between them okay I don't
understand why this four layers forward
passes just do all of the line towards
reciprocal I mean okay so this would be
pretty easy to now recode and tensor
fault this is I don't understand why the
other stuff so unreadable I mean like
these are you know get even get odd
thank you for the follows both please
subscribe I need money to buy apples
you don't apples $2.50 here it's a nice
looking Apple Bob actually they're
cheaper than that like a dollar eighty
so something give me a dollar eighty I
can afford an Apple did a lot of people
get banned
yeah so we're reading that paper it's
like okay I mean this is like a cute
trick they're using you can see what it
is now right it's a pass through and
then a transformation and a pass through
and then a transformation but it seems
diagonal scaling you know how's that
updated
maybe it's just learned so I don't know
how things are learned on here yet but
at least we understand what the the
model is inverse mapping through the
layer gradients should be turned off
through this path you're good moderator
I like you that's good thinking that's
good thinking you know mmm had a line
about that once about how he's not gonna
shoot somebody he she was gonna smack
him with the back of a pistol so that
way next time he sees him he can smack
him with the back of a pistol again just
a good life lesson guys don't shoot
people smacking with your gun no guys in
the cloudless sir it's not here
the building block has unit it's ballsy
but they're using batch norm here it's
ballsy all right so I understand the
model now which was not clear at all in
this paper like the core idea is that we
can split X into two blocks how will you
take the odd cons and the even column so
how do I understand okay this is amazing
that this works like at all
it seems stupid like it's a weird trick
we can implement that same can implement
that in tensor form or we can
[Music]
yeah Iceman ice me okay so here's the
loss function like I said I just I think
I don't wanna like do anything that
complicated
I just wanna that's good that's good
good good good timeout three timeouts
equals bana do we need another tea or
should we eat the apple who thinks tea
and who thinks apple put that hungry
maybe just a tea we'll get a tea
and how do I know how cheap these tees
are savage we've got what we're going to
you don't want to yeah I don't know I
don't like these coupling lighter things
I like the idea of just no never been
broke prom all right here's a lesson
they don't teach you in liberal arts
college like it's not like anybody he's
just gonna wake up one day and end up
poor oh okay it's a small we gonna rant
about this oh we gonna rant about like
it's a state of mind all right like
maybe there's like a couple different
mentalities of how people think about
money and you know some people and these
are the people who are gonna be poor in
life they have this idea like that like
a money's gonna rot all right and they
just gotta like spend that all
right and then they you know they they
go to the bar and they blow 80 bucks and
they put it on a credit card and it's
just like they have a poor person
mentality right and if you have that
kind of attitude toward money you're
gonna be poor arrest your life all right
you're always gonna be poor and then you
like this like middle-class attitude
toward money as much as the middle-class
may still exist but like you know they
see it as something that you know we're
gonna we're gonna work we're gonna work
towards and you work and you get paid
your money and then you pay your end
right and you have to make sure maybe
you know these people maybe even have
this idea of like savings right they're
gonna like put money away and they're
gonna save a small amount of money for
something like retirement right um and
then you have the rich people attitude
do you guys know about PE RT do you guys
know about compounding interest I
remember I was in fifth graders in an
algebra class and they tell you about
this all right you know PE RT we
can do PE RT all right so it's like you
know P times n px which is R times T
right and then P is your principal so
let's go start out with $10,000 right
$10,000 and I'm getting an interest rate
of say 10 percent and I'm getting that
interest rate um every year so let me
just think this there so then I said on
my $10,000 for 10 years
holy look at how much money I have
look at how much money I have wait I
don't think that's right I think I
messed up that's probably more correct
okay well let's see if that if that were
zero then yeah yeah so I'm making ten
percent a year look at how much money I
have right then you start to realize
what if I have a hundred thousand
dollars that isn't even that much money
but you now over ten years have turned
that into this much money let's say you
had a million dollars
you've now turned it into this much
money and let's say you captured in
there for twenty years
holy let's say you kept it in there
for a hundred years this this is like
you start out with a million dollars and
you end up with twenty two billion after
a hundred years this is how rich people
think about money like stop thinking
like like like like like oh you're gonna
get a job you don't gonna get a job you
just gotta figure out how to get some
money and then start earning interest
bro
that's you give rich so you know you
don't just go broke and the truth is
even if you ran out of money to are like
with this mentality in five years you're
rich again right you guys stop thinking
about it you see you have like the
middle-class person right and the
middle-class person they get a raise and
they're like oh now finally we can
afford our trip to to Disneyworld or we
can afford to eat nicer steaks or
like that Wow
what do you get banned for Wow y'all
gotta don't ban hey don't ban
subscribers well subscribers don't gotta
get banned that's okay but if you
subscribe you have a lot more leeway on
the you can get away with
saying on this account don't subscribe
you you didn't give me any money
if you subscribe I subscribe right
you're one of the cool people what you
say is cool right so yeah don't don't
ban the subscribers okay alright you got
to stop if you want to keep your
moderator power you can't be on this
[Laughter]
look poor people they have a terrible
attitude during money and that's why
they're poor middle-class people have an
okay attitude toward money and they'll
be middle-class for the rest of their
lives
they're not gonna struggle too hard but
they're never gonna understand what it's
what it means to like not have to worry
about money here's the trick guys if you
make $50,000 a year figure out how to
spend ten thousand you don't need
whatever they're trying to sell you
you don't need it
good life advice Joe much this tea cost
me 79 yen you know what's this apartment
cost me nothing guys nothing the only
thing in my life that I've spent any
money on was like my computer and my
phone so much this shirt cost me nothing
you know was his hair cost me Supercuts
stop spending money on that you
don't need start putting that money into
PRT all right that's today's life in my
book is a structural no they're poor
because they don't understand economics
the money should earn money this guy
gets it you shouldn't be earning money
that's the real that's really the
difference between the middle class and
the rich person attitude the middle
class person thinks they earn money the
rich person thinks their money earns
money that's a good summary two poor
people like to think like money grows on
trees they think like money falls from
the sky oh we got some money
let's go spend it on something stupid
yeah poor people thinks money grows on
trees or falls from the sky or some
you know they don't understand like
anything about like and you gotta like
work for somebody right and like you
know they're they're like no
understanding of like a business right
and this is yy-you know they're poor
middle-class people understand this
right they understand them vaguely they
have a vague inkling of this but they
still think that it's
money rich people know that money earns
money that's right and the cool thing
about this advice is it's not like easy
to do but you just got I do I do because
like you know I mean I asked you wanna
talk about people who I respect and like
someone who's poor is not very high up
on that list you know what I mean cuz
it's not like it's a all right well as
always I don't get started on fat people
you know like you know there's a lot of
things there's a lot of things you
shouldn't judge a person based on but
you can certainly judge them for being
poor and you can even judge them for
being fat what am i I don't believe in
the US dollar money is a scam made by
people to scam you have knowledge grows
ya know that's the thing man you're poor
start developing a good attitude toward
money get some money save your money
you're fat
let me tell you man stop eating crap
let's start exercising is that simple
you can stand other people out of money
too right the lake you know don't do it
okay alright alright
Ram talk rant time is over rant it's
really true it's really it's absolutely
true um there's an interview with with
Morgan Freeman where you know
interviewers talking about like you know
people from his home town rough it is so
hard to get out you know you made it out
but it's so hard
Morgan Freeman looks at him it's like
the bus runs every day yeah yeah yeah
alright alright you're poor cuz you have
a condition too no I mean people really
just don't understand what money is and
if you really it comes down to like
you're one of those three attitudes
all right let's let's get back to it
let's get back to machine learning I
wouldn't buy a Bitcoin you can't buy a
Bitcoin I was talking to someone about
like like why is Bitcoin priced at what
it is and again you know a lot of people
really don't understand economics do you
guys want to know why Bitcoin why
bitcoin is priced at what it is I'll
tell you why bitcoin is priced at what
it is go watch one Bitcoin oh it's worth
exactly one BTC one Bitcoin is worth six
thousand five hundred thirty two dollars
because exactly doesn't the official AWS
stream
well it's taking a long time to load
I'm in the cloud Bros no bitcoins price
is exactly what it is because of this
because these people up here are willing
to buy it
and these people down here are willing
to sell it and the price is just where
those two things meet right here this is
exactly what a Bitcoin is worth this
much money because these are by orders
and these are sell orders that to truly
understand what markets are supply and
demand well yeah I mean it's our what's
on the AWS stream is it any good that is
how the entire market works now really
internalize those facts all right
back to learning things here and the
number of viewers really goes up yes I
did I opened an order book and said
that's why bitcoins that price oh hey I
am machine learning at Amazon okay
alright we got a competition all right
let's start code all right
so what we're gonna try to do first we
got to understand where's that one with
twitch I don't want to not torch pyramid
that's
as it works we're reading nice could
someone link the paper please
should I just figure out to put the
paper like in the description or
something
all right now it's in the description
I'm in the clap
Wow 101 people wow so much people
alright I'll just come for the rant I
know you come for the grants know what I
want but my PI so it looks like we just
need she was trying to use by torch do I
have five torch on here it's just cool I
have fighters but let's not make this
model so complex no well I moved to
Japan because
wait a second
yeah that's no no twitch Prime is not
okay Joker I'm very sorry you were muted
I didn't want that to happen your
subscriber if you just have twitch Prime
you but if you're a subscriber to
my channel and you come here for the
premium Tom Cruise with a three content
you can get away with a lot of damn
hidden OH
so okay they can blow that up there I'm
sorry you were Bend the new moderator
was power happy thank you for
subscribing thank you I really
appreciate when people subscribe
I'm looking I'm looking at my phone down
here nothing is toxic
here is toxic everyone here it's good
attitude if we get too many people will
just shut it down and I won't stream on
Twitch anymore you know um math
prerequisites I understand the paper I
don't think there's that much like deep
math involved um I mean you should
understand what a Jacobian is like ass
cuz they use the word a lot but I don't
understand why all right let's say I
want to figure this out I mean this is
still one of the best trees we're gonna
have to solve what is a Jacobian
determinant jacobi imagination all first
order partial derivatives post its
matrix and the determinant
yeah I mean you tell my basic calculus
calculus hopefully I was understand
calculus all right um so let's try what
I was saying before about making it
invertible so let's just go whoops 784
784 and then tell you I'm going to try
to make an invertible neural map
so in theory what happens if I say like
work it's not gonna work it on and I
could make a sequential I think I have
to make a tensor out of this I don't
really know how to make just torch
tensor so eyes much oh because we're
gonna want to say reshape one let's just
say for cool
um it seems like they all went the same
yeah I considered streaming from the
transistor
maybe maybe all right so I don't really
know how to use pi torch but I feel like
I should get better at it researchers
tend to like it so big now something
like I just you know just work right
it's a slice like that I cool what's the
same thing it just seemed looks like as
an image time pie
take all numpy on the Vario that
requires grad I so we're just we're just
running through the stupid little neuron
that I made we're gonna see what we get
can I do this so that's what M this
looks like when you like visualize it
like that you know is that my phone
locked in her chest we'll probably like
some of the highlights for this channel
ever this channel is only gonna go
downhill from here
that's all I can this kind of the
distribution looks like right so we can
kind of see where things coming up with
things from the distribution why I got
dumped I can't call an umpire on
variable that requires grad to last to
be that's one way that didn't work
can't call numpy on variable that
requires grad these are detached on pi
does anyone understand what that is
thank you for subscribing thank you
thank you
time I go off thank you proteus thank
you I really appreciate when people
subscribe to my my twitch so I can
continue to buy rice and other various
food what I press ok
[Music]
what is the detach operation doing
detach does the same thing
here's an example of the difference if
you use tensor detached the gradient
computation is guaranteed to be correct
guide so anyone talking about transistor
what they were fine - is this looking up
when you get no phone he's allowed
that's right no phonies I'm looking into
a little bit more
it's a online course I'm gonna have to
find an FPGA board I like grad okay
February you don't have yours my
favorite time all right let's try to do
the thing let's try that yeah it doesn't
look like that right so we're going this
figure there so that's what the input
distribution and that's what the output
distribution looks like you should be
able to learn like the amnesty inverter
right so by George train
um just write a quick trainer so the
60,000 things will do batch sizes of say
100 will say why why those models up X
chain o plus 100 I was just trying to
tries that as the ass that is extra that
shape sub-zero cool f dot n ll loss
backwards optimizer don't step
all right so let's just write a quick
trainer can you see or is this the part
I can't say model train no that means
you look at this a loss
optimist not define getting a qdm EDM is
on my favorite looking never your ass I
said yesterday isn't there a tiki DM
around this will get a little progress
bar boom alright well I'll just went to
Nan's did it go to Nance so here it goes
to Nance and so much Nance
so much dance
and why is that happening
[Music]
pouches full just not being a knitted oh
hello I was a model about liars
even to type ipython notebook
[Music]
okay snap a scan the same questions
let's put the Jake Paul sweatshirt on
I'm getting cold
there we go I can't go away to this
don't wait
all right so now we train and they all
become mad okay I do wrong
nothing go down exciting to optimize
your step
what do i do optimizers depakote than
that let's do one step few steps man
that much steps
now
not in man now I'm stable you know
what's always stable Adam here's Adam
I'll look Adam always stable so slow
though beautiful see what it looks like
now okay good so now you can see that it
matches all right so let's learn the
inverse Adams an optimize our google it
all right so this learns to inverted
mists so now let's take a sample it's
just a model extra choice works we have
to say like X check this sob an
inclusive or exclusive perfect probably
you know it was a probabilistic test
shape sub-zero model exchange CC sixty
plus one detached numpy we should
actually just say I wish you call this X
attacks
- OH xx die already
okay wait 28 all this one y model X X
now we learn a nice numpy inverter built
in our groups
yeah look this upside down alright so
you see my function learn to turn that
into that oh yeah oh yeah get it get it
alright let's add in a bunch more stupid
layers and see if it gets to learn it I
was gonna take forever because no GPU oh
come on the GPU you guys I'm poor and
poor on GPU so learn that words ok
inverter hi whoo ok so we're turning
threes into backward 3 inverter hi cool
that's good that's good
now let's invert the function and see if
it can turn this into that well first
let's just try it I mean this model
hypothetically should just be so work
let me go
Oh to Python 3 now we have Python 3
programmer that's 110 said oh so we have
to say ten sir why why I want to do it
up there
name ten so it's not defined torch top
ten center
okay so it kind of works in the universe
but like not really right so but that
didn't actually invert the function I
just like put it in because the function
is like the inversor itself it's
knocking now we should actually be able
to completely invert this because
matrices can be inverted and because Lu
can be inverted when you figure how to
do this there isn't that and
sublime said some stuff about that I
didn't pipe I this morning
oh and D FAA yeah those four CTF no
stupid coupling law thing no this is way
better I'm actually inverting the model
so they made a claim in their paper
we're not trying to copy the paper
exactly I don't totally understand the
paper I think the best way to understand
it is to like build something that's
like not exactly the right thing but
yeah so they're saying they make some
claim one way to use this observation
would be to build a neural network with
triangular weight matrices and by
ejective activation functions so we are
using a bioactive activation function
the Lu function is by jected limiting
design choices to depth to depth like
get it okay fine
so we have this thing called model we
can say
um can you guys see this okay by the way
I didn't like my face is there should I
put my face up here I can move my face I
like code over there
hey face up here so better cool and now
I'm like coding over here that's like
that I'm sorry okay how the first one is
a stupid one the first one is this
sequential isn't what I want
children children okay yes they're
children because there's nothing special
about a sequential okay so I should
actually be able to invert that a linear
layer oh they have biases should we
retrain this without the bias bias is
bad people well learn okay we fill say
let's find out let's take so long guards
please don't leave subscribe so I can
afford a GPO I'm only on CPU you know
CPU it's so slow
Oh guys we got rid of the bias cuz
somebody want to deal with um let's Jack
here it's a really work then he did buy
us
ok broke garbage I'll have to invert the
bias to
[Music]
I have a great iPhone this one
and you know it works I don't know I
guess we need bias okay it works is
biased only with mice Wow
my CPUs bottle to the moon okay
it's a by winning a lair
by linear transformation I mean you're
like by linear interpolation
what's a bilinear transformation you
know adds them weird okay
if Tyco bad just type in what I want
here and so I'm gonna try to invert this
neural network right and in that linear
time equals a little in here down that's
great
didn't work no it's the name of the cat
allah go oh I cam that waits Waits
yeah okay so why timed up by is touch it
so what it is cool okay so now inverse X
I don't want to say this we don't say so
first we have to subtract the bias and
then P and move m dot wait
well first let's let's just do compute X
and make sure I wrote this right they
had a real name for it they called it
yes forward inverse that's too forward
first actually I understand how these
things work
this should be really easy if I did it
right okay if type equals linear it's
probably like a nicer way to do this but
what we want to say is okay so they're
claiming it's x transpose X and if you
down x and wait T plus I'm done Pius X
eight-balls
I'll tell you
although he acts like you ways to do
this and numpy isn't there yeah so we
just say like an x equals x less than
zero
and we got X this is actually correct
isn't that this x + X + NP down X minus
1 X equals ax ax
all right so if we did that right
we should say y equals forward X X sub 0
0 that parameter object has no attribute
t1 point can't call a lump on variable
that requires grad oh but I did detach
to detach the bias probably 200 here
unsupported type for nun type maybe that
is just that parameter object has an
electric t can't call number oh we're
gonna have a name for the matrix here
they call it a let's just say a little
I'm not waiting I'm pi not te let's also
move this here can't call numpy on
variable that requires grant all right
it's gold attached here whatever that
means
okay seems good unsupported type oh I
don't know a transpose or nun type X
none type
Wow turn acts oops
um NP Tylenol stop transpose oops
numpad transpose I'm show xx we shape
show why why are we shape okay that
works cool all right so that's oh wow
wait how did that work it has no bias
that's so weird
well actually I kind of understand it
it's actually cause of how M show works
cult
so now just lets you know throwing up is
easy here let's actually add this up
here okay so that like kind of works but
not really so let's try this with
inverse okay runs up through some values
okay so we want on Lu what's the inverse
of the expo
where's my graphic value it's somewhere
isn't it yeah so the inverse value is
just going to be whatever the inverse of
the X function is what is the university
export universe and px who knows that
it's just- alright it double negative
okay so how do we undo that so you undo
that is you multiply that by just the
inverse of this and beat ugly now all
the ton inv so if this worked this thing
would look like that but it is I'm wrong
I think my in value is correct we can
test it quickly
plot should be a straight line it's not
temesta
does that not work even
gonna work
what are you wrong
exampie copy ax nags Alex less than 0 XM
x equals NP x one day I'll stop doing
that oh it's cracked
it seems crack just looks shitty when
you're ok so it should be right
no it's not right
ok looks right but it's not right ok so
a few things you know +1 in here the
inverse function is different what is it
do you know what it is not that not that
ok whoa for mouth
so what's the inverse wait isn't the
inverse of e to the X just long there
you go
well I'm dumb of course it's long this
literally Wow okay I'm stupid
that's cool no jail I know it's knowing
of the inverse value function and if I
got my matrices right okay that's still
wrong so now let's think about what I'm
doing wrong with matrices just closed W
Gavea nope no ox okay um if we have
something and we dot it with something
oh no I'm the worst perhaps ever that No
is it possible to just do inverse on
this whole thing can I just say towards
dot inverse model know what that means
no chasing if it's the square matrix
okay this is firm paychecks and we could
write it but I don't think it's not like
it's a pretty read the layers okay
this is just good for now so let's
figure out why doesn't work NP the
knowledge inverse okay so X dot W
dot W to the minus one should be the
opposite is it lagging lag what's up
okay this should look like something in
the hologram
I mean this work should unless these
matrices are like poorly conditioned or
something I'm sorry it's lagging guys
I'll buy more Internet I had a place
this is the same thing as saying X dot W
right let's like try something stupid
that's like a de transpose here
oops
yes and that breaks that so yeah you get
this wrong it breaks
you might check to see if these things
are the same
I really wish they'd changed the print
function back in Python 3 so it can be
supported both ways but they're dicks
and they won't do it
see if that works like are those the
same yeah they look pretty similar
what is the right thing do you like see
the benefit bro
doing a band brow what band band
stupid question is that okay um
[Music]
what does my in value work for a long
time to a certain amount
yeah I mean like it fix it with tools
but you know it's always better to
change your behavior than to like add
some custom environment ship it's better
when I do that why doesn't my inverse
work okay I don't understand all right
let's keep track of all the
intermediates
I'll see where they begin to diverge
they diverted by the first thing your
liar
no I haven't diverged appreciably by the
first linear way the alley layers wrong
but in value doesn't work
I don't know why I was like okay doesn't
it make sense actually so that should be
that should be the output those are
completely identical it was a change a
tiny bit but within like numerical
instability of matrix inversion that is
broken entirely even for things that
just shouldn't be broken at all like
these ones okay something's going wrong
with my Lu inversion
right now I just shouldn't do anything I
don't get it now
those two are definitely the same that
was the first one I upended that's
actually just the same as why why yeah
bro if you're subscribing because you
think you will get something you're
subscribing for the wrong reasons
information is free if you're
subscribing because you know you want to
give me money that's a good reason to
subscribe if you're subscribing because
you want something don't subscribe
torrent it figure out how to get it for
free bro that's the best way to do it
because free is great I love free I'm a
big fan of free
[Music]
okay well what should happen between
here and here is Lu ya see that one only
changes the negative values here
something stupids happening it's like
even changing the positive values but it
doesn't make sense because when I call
this out no now it doesn't do anything
is in value broken
when I test it
yeah see look okay something's really
wrong yeah cuz that's just doing that
see that's correct
see that's correct something else must
be happening what's happening to go from
there to there that's not an L you 8 8 8
8 8 8 3 3 y 0 it's just the first one in
one
yeah doesn't make sounds you see what
you see what's like I was happening here
I know what's happening
always copy try save memory cheap fogs
okay that's better now it all looks
correct those are the same those the
same
those are the same hmm this one broke
okay let's go back to a simpler model
learn to fine don't need to plot this
okay that works okay huh I guess just
one of the matrices wasn't very well
invertible seems to work okay now like
that solid spicy inverse yeah bro let me
tell you the difference man you ever
seen Jeff Bezos talk to you and read
your comment but you really gotta give
me money right if you're debating about
subscribing don't but at the same time
please subscribe like if you're thinking
about the utility that subscribing will
give to you then you're the wrong kind
of person and please leave the channel
right like if you're the kind of person
who's thinking like maybe if I subscribe
I could learn something for like a job
interview then you get off the
channel if you are subscribing for the
sheer Glee of clicking the subscribe
buttons and so you can have a little
star next to your name that is why you
should subscribe you people with the
Stars are better than the people without
the Stars you see everybody has a name
on twitch right and they're right here
here are the names on twitches you
seeker anagen he is better than jib
palely you see joker 2k nine nine nine
he is better than her do and if you're
harder I'm sorry I didn't ask for your
preferred pronouns if you're a
subscriber I will ask you everyone who's
not a subscriber you're just they okay
you Paul yerko have star you are better
than P
who don't have star that's how it works
okay so that's the only question you
gotta ask yourself do you wanna be
better than the people without star
that's it that's the reason you should
subscribe that's a good reason ten
there's a good reason
can I subscribe that was want to
subscribe
do I have star I have star
I'll see that's good I'm happy ahead
star it's in my notifications I have so
much friends requests do you oh okay
alright alright alright let's go back to
the paper I think I know what I did I
think I know what was the problem
I think numerical instabilities are
adding up mmm that works does this work
there's a little bit of noise and the
problem is once I add an another layer
there's too much noise excellent bro
excellent please subscribe though until
you have a star you know the kind the
worst kind of people are the people who
say they're gonna subscribe an adult man
I'm counting my money over here don't
look oh that's not that much money any
more people to subscribe
followers you're worthless to me you
don't get a star I mean I guess you're
better to not followers but to be honest
if this channel gets too popular and we
if we ever felt like a thousand viewers
on the channel we'd have to shut it down
like the day we had a thousand viewers
is the day we shut down the Tom Cruise
with the three twitch channel everyone
else like everyone else I'm sure there's
other people like this bro maybe we just
start banning people for spreading anti
subscriber propaganda why can't we be
too popular because do you know you act
differently you know you act when you're
in like a room with your friends you're
pretty cool everything's chill and
everything's relaxed but you know when
you're not chill when you're like
speaking to an audience of a thousand
people you can't be chill anymore it
can't just be like the Tom Cruise with
the three switch channels twitch channel
is just a cool place to hang out like
it's a cool place to hang out we code we
should talk and that's what it is okay
so I am now understanding one of the
things they said in the paper
let's bring the paper back and then I
think we might always to be on streaming
for today but we wrote an invertible
neural network the problem is it doesn't
nicely invert nice there's that word
again nice so this is only the relayer
Network and you can already start to see
the noise appearing in the picture dance
once Thanos
Oh panels
Plus Thanos I don't understand
I don't watch Avengers movies I guess I
saw the first Avengers just a little
load with the paper go there's a paper
um well these are these woke you know
have limiting design choices to depth
and selection nonlinearities mmm okay
but this might have more to do with the
numeric approximation of NP Lin algin
see if I can get a better one
look at that noise it's disgusting noise
Dan else's
it's from superhero movies isn't it
how much beauty 500 but I did watch this
thing on a Gucci that was pretty good
and I don't really watch that much
YouTube anymore the beginning of this
year I watched a lot of YouTube I've
just been reading a lot I read a lot of
papers read books
everyone's happy in the cloud all right
inverting triangular matrices
Flattr its bro guys haven't you been on
Google Maps lately haven't you been on
Google Maps they're really pushing that
around Earth propaganda just zoom out on
Google Maps wow my internet it's
flat it's flat and then they push the
propaganda wow that took some time you
saw a Catcher in the Rye it's a movie
they made a Catcher in the Rye movie
rebel and the RAI hosted you 4-0 viewers
you guys have yours wait who said
politics no so many politics work
slavery problem everything is politics
yes Segway slavery and then they're
gonna make you bi and that's the right
slavery they but it wasn't a movie it's
a good it's a good movie it's a good
book I mean yeah I want you catching
that I what's the name of the ml book I
was reading
look at my books oh I guess I looked at
this um yesterday I mean this is just
like the classic it's just that yeah I
modern approach I own the physical book
I own the physical book go buy it go
support the authors if it actually
supports the authors if it supports a
Marisol publishing company just toured
it this is a good book
this one's interesting Hardy's theory of
numbers I read this this this was very
quick to read Jonathan Livingston
Seagull it was alright I don't know I
wouldn't really recommend it
I'd recommend catching the ride that I
read I read this I read prime obsession
this was cool and yeah that's that
physical I don't know any physical books
from the cloud bro no physical here
Hogan's cloud okay so today we learned
about invertible neural networks you've
been streaming for two and a half hours
I think streaming time might be almost
over we didn't get through this paper
yet but we understand the beginning of
it a little bit maybe tomorrow we'll
stream more this paper structure and
interpretation of computer programs
this papers legit yeah no it's a good
paper um what is this
when was this written they have
computers in 1996 I'm probably gonna
work on this more tomorrow without you
guys trying to understand this
yeah polyfill test tomorrow without you
guys
but look what what do you want - what do
you want to stream tomorrow why should I
read this it's kind of interesting
registers to the exercises our discover
this random exercise accumulate
procedures known as fold right there's
also a fold left language is this like
bliss or skew or something no no we're
not streaming when I streaming tutorials
let me know if you have come up with
something to write tomorrow we can write
it yes less you know oh there's a cool
uh it's hard learn tasks Oh sounds
pretty cool no no no the GPU we can't do
real neural network stuff but we thought
we thought a little about invertibility
of neural networks today what is this
link
I do love functional programming I like
you more like the provable programming
languages I haven't played with him that
much but like there's which is very
poorly named I was doing some
tutorials
no no don't stop with the plural
networks we did some neural network
stuff today and then stuff is mostly
just people doing like flashy garbage
it's 9:17 am I talking too loud for the
cloud baby no no see this year you're
talking to a flashy garbage
this is flashy garbage I checked if you
were a subscriber are you gonna write
your own language no I was looking into
our Python today myself cutting Roman
it's all the links I clicked project you
alright six to do the hexagon
[Laughter]
accepting donations there behind into
that realize never in broadcast social
eating category
what's your startup plan Gaussian
processes I mean that's more interesting
now if we're gonna stream or m/l stuff
we're just gonna do more we're gonna
like go back to this paper like the
thing about ml stuff is it like kind of
works always okay so actually where was
I with invertible neural networks we can
we can do some casual stuff while we
figure out what we're gonna do next
stream yeah social meetings overrated
kind of agree with that should I eat my
Apple or if your abdominals can you get
a personal pizza from dominos
that was a miss click in Japanese I want
Domino's Japan but in English an apple a
day turns you gay single pizza to go one
smile was this this answers hope you
know I'm in English language wait for
500 yen I can get English
pick up your order at a Domino's store I
don't they have pizza odds here I know
the Domino's I saw it it's around the
corner place where station named Osaka
wait what
none of the either near me oh that one
maybe it's kinda near me you guys Ted
I'm a member sheesh store
oh sweet yes because it's not really
close to me I'm gonna have to walk a
while to get there um single pizza to go
no thanks wait I don't want any of these
for one person I'm only one person I'm
in the cloud guys don't worry wait I
don't want a pizza sandwich
Pizza menu yeah you you guys actually
sent somebody to meet me at Domino's I'd
be so impressed what no one smile Rach
these are expensive what happened to my
thousand yen Pizza how much calories is
this it's probably too much calories
I see that's why the stream can't be too
popular
giga meat pizza sandwich where you get
pizza sandwich all right we go back to
special order special offers to actually
want Domino's guys you think pizzas and
one looks good but what should we stream
tomorrow let me know and I'll be excited
about it all day and I'll prepare for it
no they had a good but they had a good
deal I don't know what happened to it I
just like the idea of Domino's okay I
want like oh yeah what are you doing do
you paying she look I got a thousand
yen's and we're gonna spend it at
Domino's well tomato rich premium
margarita single pizza to go for pickup
one smile range
see but okay so I don't understand how
oh my god this is so difficult I look at
that ad special offers though but how
come there was that special offer I know
I was like $8 so I hate how do I get
back to that special offer for
joking dominoes browse somewhere
Domino's yeah okay so how do I get the
1,000 yen pizza cuz I'm poor pick up
your order at a doll pickup perk song
Osaka not there from there
that's the one I'm near okay
hey man people of all socio-economic
classes can single pizza to go I
definitely don't want to pizza pickup
single pizza to go now do I get how do I
get discount pizza menu people of all
socio-economic statuses this
I can't afford these expensive pizzas
campaign pizza does that politics pick
up single pizza to go
pennilyn two pizzas how they really op
selling me on double cheese pan pizza
ultra crispy cheese burst well there's a
surcharge for that crust and award
alright do I actually want a pizza guys
should I stick with you if you wasn't
here guys want to come for a walk we'll
pick up the pizza
no I don't want sides wow really
upselling me here I'm so poor I got
literally the cheapest pizza I can get
alright guys I'm in Japan I'm not
ordering a pizza
that's disgusting I'm gonna eat the
apple and that's gonna be the end of the
stream all right so here's Apple keeps
off the stream I'm not inviting you guys
to pizza look at the size of this Apple
for comparison here's an iPhone 8 choose
an apple and here's an apple they're the
same size do I have I think I have to
wash the Apple I'm gonna go wash the
Apple what do we want to stream next
stream
fool your hands daily expense Snapple $2
in the u.s. mid challenge like slamming
chess were like good challenges
[Applause]
the problem is CTF in project you
lose they don't like when they you
scream their
I already did chest chest and go her the
same thing
I'm really bad afford I was this there's
a rotten bit in my Apple companies are
stupid there's people who like rice
together 27 million models believe in
bought for tonight that something
fundamental something on Twitch s or
twitch slam like what could be next
twitch what huh no no I haven't seen any
sex balls I don't know where one would
go to get that I don't speak Japanese
what's Twitter Mary hmm right in NES
emulator that's not fun I've never
written an emulator before well so
what processor guys you know what
language we're writing it in Python
hmm questions like how much
peripherals are there
yeah I'm really there's our boy what
else okay it's been done tons of times
what else do we have what are they
making yeah I don't want to implement
all the stupid op codes emulated test
engine we brought a chess engine guys I
mean I'm interested in like I'm
interested in like yeah we got on the
slam my game I wrote like a little dev
world for it it's in twitch line now I'm
interested in like proving computation
all right there's apples too big to eat
do you think it's like closed s and put
it in the fridge it's still be good
tomorrow morning
does that Apple is more than one serving
of Apple but it was actually a really
good Apple in the US if you got an apple
that big or tall it tastes pretty
disgusting what's our master hacker what
is our master hacker
know that stuff means now I'm interested
let's let my interests now are in like
provable computation I'm not good at
this stuff though I don't go and write
up that much I think I've seen this
before
their cycle rhythms parsing algorithm
for context-free grammars no we're not
billing shitty hang like things yeah
I've seen this before
pretty cool bro pretty cool Moore's law
and I'm you're late man so marched you
like Misra C no no that's like
automotive
I mean like like cops are right over
there here where they even go with us I
mean like concert
hi guys to my big one
math
and it takes all the Bitcoin does does
does a good stream no but I so I'm
taking ideas I don't know how you can
send them to me you probably can't so
I'm just gonna think about what stream
is gonna be and we'll do it tomorrow
don't drink tea well I finished the
Bitcoin thing like today yeah you want
to see what uh what CPU my back as I'm
gonna see if it's vulnerable to talk
back to the paper yeah okay we'll do the
paper more tomorrow let's gonna do
tomorrow but for now I'm leaving you
guys going down with us dominoes get the
dollar is Domino's sugar it bros teeth
nice no not really get pizza see you
guys later